# D. Sunil kumar 🕡 Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Project Management, Web Development, System Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Technical Analysis, HTML, Javascript, Java, Eclipse, SQL Server, JQuery



Current Designation: Senior Software Developer Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Vitech Systems Asia

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Application Programming, Project Management, Web Development, System Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Technical Analysis, HTML, Javascript, Java, Eclipse, SQL Server, JQuery, Spring

Boot, React. Js, senior s, GWT, Tapestry, PLSQL, Jenkins

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

## Summary

10+ years of experience in IT industry in application software programming using Java / J2EE technologies. To achieve a challenging position in software organization where my analytical and application skills can be explored for successful completion of project and as well as for growth of the organization.

## Work Experience

Vitech Systems Asia as Senior Software Developer Jun 2016 to Till Date

**Vitech Systems Asia** as Senior Software Engineer May 2016 to Jun 2016

Project Name: V3 Product. Duration: May 2016 to Till Date

Technologies: Spring (Restful web services), Sprring Boot, React JS, Maven, GWT, Tapesry, PL/SQL,

SVN, Post gress, JQuery and Tomcat.

Desccription:

The entire V3 product is broadly divided into various business modules based on the services they offer and based on the activities performed on each Module, which are listed as followed: World, Contributions, SCP, Pension, Workflow, CRM, Disbursements, Claims, Documents and Batches.

Each of the above module interact with one another to fulfill user's request.V3 also comprises of various low level technical services (or modules) which are commonly used by all the modules above when needed and are listed as follows:

Security b) Imports & Exports c) Reports d) Documents e) Batches

#### Role and responsibilities:

- \* Development of feature enhancement.
- \* Taking training sessions on world Related module.
- \* Analysis of Client Problems, Implementation and fixing bugs.

#### Oracle financial services Pvt. Ltd as Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2012 to Dec 2015

Project Name : Actimize - GIDB. Duration : Jan 2012 to Dec 2015

Technology: java, JSP, springs, Hibernate, WebServise, JQuery, Web Spear, Oracle, Java script, CSS, HTML

Role : Developer.
Client : CITI.
Domain : Banking.

Description

Global Investigations Data base with Interactive User Interface. The primary purpose of this proposed system is to facilitate global investigations of questionable activity through consistent collection and treatment of needed data, metrics reporting, with the overall goal of meeting Citi's regulatory filing obligations for the countries identified for phase 1 (Appendix 10.1) implementation.

This functional requirements document is based on Business Requirements specified and elaborates details on the functionality. The proposed solution will be accessible to users within the Citi internal network through the Citi standard IE web browser.

Responsibilities:

As a team member, was responsible for

Create cases using AIS.

Implement mail component with xsl attachment for report time line module.

Implement JReports using RCM designer.

Releasing SN requests.

Prepare CCF document and Release note using QCExplorer.

Involved in Change Requests

Analysis of Change Requests, involved in coding and Implementation of the Change Requests etc.

Involved in manual testing, Unit Testing and Integration Testing.

Involved in coding.

Analysis of Client Problems, Implementation and fixing of the bugs.

Involved in Production Support.

#### **Polaris Software Lab Limited**

Oct 2009 to May 2010

Project Name : ITCOSTMANAGEMENT
Duration : Oct 2009 to May 2010

Technology: java, JSP, Struts1.x, Dojo, IBaits, JSon, PL/Sql, Java script, CSS, HTML

Role : Development.

Description :

Provide information about Servers and Applications related to a cost center. An Owner who maps the Server with this Application. We will roll up through cost centers of validate to find the owner. If while rolling up, we found a cost center which is already associated with this Server, we will attach this application to this Server through that owner. Percentage of Ownership - Since the validate of the Server

Application association is not giving any information about the cost center directly. How should percentage be allocated Do we need to design uniform distribution for this as well

Application Percentage - User can allocate percentage to his newly associated application. If the percentage of already associated applications adds up to 100, user can be asked to reduce the percentage of others so as to accommodate the percentage of his newly associated application. User shall be prompted for uniform distribution of the applications attached.

Responsibilities:

As a team member, was responsible for

Developed scripts for continuously running Tomcat and Apache servers using

VB script and bat file and schedule tasks.

Developed code for sending mail including body image.

Learn dojo, Ibatis, Cahche, and JSon quickly and implement in the application.

Implement URL's for The Application using Tomcat server files and virtual host.

Performed manual testing.

Involved in Unit Testing and Integration Testing.

Involved in coding.

Analysis of Client Problems, Implementation and fixing of the bugs.

Involved in Production Support.

### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Nagarjuna University in 2001

PG: MCA (Computers) from Madras University in 2004

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
JSP, Web Servises, Struts, Spring			
Hibernate, iBatis, JQuery,Ant			
Spring Boot, React Js			
Windows XP, Windows 2000, Unix			
Java, HTML, Java Script			
Eclipse, IS, RCM Designer, JReport			
Tomcat, Web Sphere, WebLogic			
Oracle, MS SQL Server			
spring boot	2.1.2	2020	2 Year(s)
React.js		2020	2 Year(s)

### Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Telugu	Expert			

## **Projects**

Project Title: Actimize - GIDB.

Client: CITI

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2012 - Dec 2015

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: Global Investigations Data base with Interactive User Interface. The primary purpose of this proposed system is to facilitate global investigations of questionable activity through consistent collection and treatment of needed data, metrics reporting, with the overall goal of meeting Citi's regulatory filing obligations for the countries identified for phase 1 (Appendix 10.1) implementation.

This functional requirements document is based on Business Requirements specified and elaborates details on the functionality. The proposed solution will be accessible to users within the Citi internal network through the Citi standard IE web browser.

### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time